orangehrm.com 2019-06-12

# 

OrangeHRM Privacy Policy
                  (​Revision April 2018​)

This Privacy Policy covers the privacy practices OrangeHRM employs when OrangeHRM
Website visitors (“Visitor”, “You”) visit and individuals who register to use OrangeHRM
services. This privacy policy applies to data provided on or through OrangeHRM website
located at www.orangehrm.com, (the “Service”). This Privacy Policy does not cover any
information or data collected by OrangeHRM Cloud-Based Enterprise application, For such
information Please refer to the OrangeHRM Service Privacy Policy.
Who We are
When we talk about “OrangeHRM”, or “us” or “we” in this policy, we are talking about
OrangeHRM Inc.
Data Protection Officer
Our Data Protection Officer oversees how we collect, use, share and protect your information to
ensure your rights are fulfilled. You can contact our Data Protection Officer at
dpo@orangehrm.com
What Information Do We Collect?
When a User registers with OrangeHRM, information is needed such as the Visitor’s name,
company name, contact telephone number and business email address. When a Visitor contacts
us and/or requests information about OrangeHRM, we will collect the Visitor’s email address
and other contact information so that we may fulfill the Visitor’s request. Some information
provided to us may, either alone or when connected with other information such as Internet
protocol address,Internet service provider, operating system, the site from which you arrived, and
the time and date of your visit, may individually identify a Visitor, and that information may be
referred to in this Privacy Policy as “Personal Information.”
We also collect information through the use of a technology called "cookies." A cookie is a small
file that a website can send to your browser, which is then stored on your system by your
browser. The use of cookie technology on the Service orangehrm.com is solely for internal
purposes.
How do we use your information?
OrangeHRM uses information, including Personal Information, provided by you to provide the
Services and for business purposes, It includes processing and fulfilling quote requests,
                                                                                                  1

customization requests, Newsletters, Sales follow-ups and Helpdesk assistance on services such
as OrangeHRM trials and Demo’s
If you apply for a job with us, we will collect, process and store the information you provide to
us for recruitment purposes. We may also retain some of your information for a reasonable
period of time for purposes of considering you for future positions.
OrangeHRM will not share your Personal Information, or otherwise, make your Personal
Information available to any other parties except as provided in this Privacy Policy. We will not
sell, rent, or exchange your Personal Information with any third-parties without permission from
you.
How do we protect your information?
We maintain a comprehensive, written information security program that contains industry
standard, administrative, technical, and physical safeguards designed to prevent unauthorized
access to your Data.
Our infrastructure service provider is Rackspace Inc, They maintain various certifications to
assist us in verifying the security policies, processes and facilitate applicable laws such as GDPR
and international standards. Rackspace has been assessed and hold validation for the following
compliance frameworks.
    ● ISO 27001​ - Rackspace ISO 27001 certified Information Security Management System
         (ISMS) is an iterative management system that helps ensure security policies and
         processes are effective in mitigating identified risks. ISMS at Rackspace certifies the
         management of information security in the operations of their data center facilities.
    ● SSAE 16 and ISAE 3402​ (Previously SAS 70 Type II) - Rackspace type II to SOC
         report can be used to satisfy requirements under both the SSAE 16 and ISAE 3402
         standards. This report contains a description of the controls in place and the auditors
         informed opinion of how effective the controls were during the audit period.
    ● PCI DSS​ - A qualified security assessor(QSA) validates Rackspace being a PCI DSS
         Level 1 service provider. It covers.
             ○ Physical security for data centers.
Your personal information rights
You may correct, update, amend, or remove Personal Information by requesting us to do so. You
may contact us on ​info@orangehrm.com​ and request for the modification. If you no longer
desire to use our Services, you may deactivate the Services by contacting us via email. You may
withdraw your consent to our processing of your Personal Information at any time by contacting
us using the contact information listed in the orangehrm.com website, but that will mean we can
no longer provide the Service to you. We will respond to your requests regarding changes to
                                                                                                   2

Personal Information or Service changes promptly, but in any event within 30 days of your call
or receipt of your request.
How long we keep your information
We keep your information for as long as you have a valid registration. We will retain and use
your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce
our agreement. If you request us to purge your information via ​info@orangehrm.com​, We will
respond to you within 30 days and purge your information. Upon purging. Such information will
be completely removed from OrangeHRM backups after 30 days.
Meeting our legal and regulatory obligations
OrangeHRM may, where it concludes that it is legally obligated to do so, disclose personal data
to law enforcement or other government authorities. OrangeHRM will notify Customer of such
request unless prohibited by law.
Consent
When we use sensitive personal information about you for any service enhancement, we ask for
your consent. Before you give your consent, we tell you what information we collect and what
we use it for. You can remove your consent at any time by contacting us.
Cookies
Strictly Necessary Cookies
 These cookies are necessary for the website to function and cannot be switched off in our
systems. They are usually only set in response to actions made by you which amount to a request
for services, such as setting your privacy preferences, logging in or filling in forms. You can set
your browser to block or alert you about these cookies, but some parts of the site will not then
work. These cookies do not store any personally identifiable information. Cookies used
        • OptanonConsent
        • OptanonAlertBoxClosed
        • PHPSESSID
                                                                                                    3

Performance Cookies
 These cookies allow us to count visits and traffic sources so we can measure and improve the
performance of our site. They help us to know which pages are the most and least popular and
see how visitors move around the site. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and
therefore anonymous. If you do not allow these cookies we will not know when you have visited
our site, and will not be able to monitor its performance. Cookies used
        • __utmb
        • __utma
        • __utmz
        • _gat
        • _gid
        • __utmc
        • __utmt
        • _ga
        • __utmv
Functional Cookies
These cookies enable the website to provide enhanced functionality and personalisation.
They may be set by us or by third party providers whose services we have added to our pages. If
you do not allow these cookies then some or all of these services may not function properly.
Cookies used
        • orangehrm
        • __unam
 Targeting Cookies
 These cookies may be set through our site by our advertising partners. They may be used by
those companies to build a profile of your interests and show you relevant adverts on other sites.
They do not store directly personal information, If you do not allow these cookies, you will
experience less targeted advertising. Categories
Pardot.com
        • Cookies lpv210042
        • visitor_id210042
        • pardot
        • visitor_id210042-hash facebook.com
                                                                                                  4

        • datr
        • x-src
        • fr
        • lu
        • locale youtube.com
        • SID
        • HSID
        • demographics
        • VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE
        • PREF
        • APISID
        • SSID
        • LOGIN_INFO
        • YSC
        • SAPISID
Making a Complaint
If you have a complaint about the use of your personal information, OrangeHRM privacy policy
or OrangeHRM security, Please contact our DPO through dpo@orangehrm.com.
Updates to this notice
We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to its information practices. If We make
any material changes, We will notify by means of a notice on this site prior to the change
becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information
on our privacy practices.
                                                                                               5
